[
    {
        "qnum": 1,
        "question": "Who does the author hold responsible for the shooting spree in schools and colleges?",
        "options": [
            "Only A",
            "Only C",
            "Only B and C",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "section": "Reading Comprehension"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 2,
        "question": "According to the passage, which of the following is a reason for poverty and hunger in underdeveloped countries?",
        "options": [
            "Only B",
            "Only C",
            "Only A",
            "Not mentioned in the passage"
        ],
        "answer": "Only A",
        "section": "Reading Comprehension"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 3,
        "question": "What does the author mean by \u2018intercepting someone\u2019s share of daily bread\u2019?",
        "options": [
            "Hindering the process of marketing in underdeveloped countries by the developed countries",
            "Denying material comfort to the Western world",
            "Affecting the social life of those working towards material comforts only",
            "Excess of wealth in western world while people in poorer nations struggle for survival"
        ],
        "answer": "Excess of wealth in western world while people in poorer nations struggle for survival",
        "section": "Reading Comprehension"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 4,
        "question": "The author\u2019s main objective in writing the passage is:",
        "options": [
            "To explain that consumerist societies have their own drawbacks which are over blinded by its material glare",
            "To explain how too many material comforts have improved the living standard of common man in the west",
            "That young children should not be given access to guns and other ammunitions",
            "All NRIs are leading unmindful, second-class lives abroad"
        ],
        "answer": "To explain that consumerist societies have their own drawbacks which are over blinded by its material glare",
        "section": "Reading Comprehension"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 5,
        "question": "The price of a Washing Machine today is Rs. 15,000. What was its price 2 years back if the yearly rate of inflation is 20%?",
        "options": [
            "Less than Rs. 10,000",
            "More than Rs.10,000 but less than Rs.11,000",
            "More than Rs.11,000 but less than Rs.12,000",
            "More than Rs. 12,000"
        ],
        "answer": "More than Rs.10,000 but less than Rs.11,000",
        "section": "Quantitative Aptitude"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 6,
        "question": "There is triangle ABC & the sides of a triangle are 5, 12 & 13 units. The rectangle PQRS is having the same area as that of triangle ABC. What would be the difference between the perimeters of rectangle PQSR & triangle ABC if we know the width of rectangle PQRS is 10 unit?",
        "options": [
            "Less than 10",
            "More than 10 & less than 20",
            "20",
            "25"
        ],
        "answer": "More than 10 & less than 20",
        "section": "Quantitative Aptitude"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 7,
        "question": "ABC Ltd. has employed 3 kinds of professionals- Engineers, Managers & Accountants. Further, 83% Engineers are females. Also, 76% managers are females & 85% accountants are females. Among Engineers & Managers there are 79% females. Also, among Managers & accountants there are 81% females. What is the percentage of male employees in ABC Ltd?",
        "options": [
            "12.5%",
            "15.5%",
            "18.5%",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "18.5%",
        "section": "Quantitative Aptitude"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 8,
        "question": "Two persons A and B start from the opposite ends of a Corridor. They first meet 45 m from one of the ends. They continue their journey reach the other end and turn back. If they now meet 25 m from the other end, find the length of the corridor?",
        "options": [
            "70 m",
            "90 m",
            "110 m",
            "140 m"
        ],
        "answer": "110 m",
        "section": "Quantitative Aptitude"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 9,
        "question": "Riyan has 60 candies that he wants to divide among himself and his 12 friends. The candies don\u2019t necessarily have to be divided equally, but each person must get at least 1 candy. If Arihant wants to have more candies than any of his friends, what is the difference between largest & least number of candies he could have?",
        "options": [
            "35",
            "38",
            "42",
            "Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "answer": "42",
        "section": "Quantitative Aptitude"
    },
    {
        "qnum": 10,
        "question": "Sales volume of company B increased by 20% in 2009 over 2008. What is the percentage change in the total sales volume of 2009 over the total sales volume of 2008?",
        "options": [
            "25%",
            "50%",
            "75%",
            "cannot be determined"
        ],
        "answer": "50%",
        "section": "Data Interpretation"
    }
]